iapplicants.com 2010-11-18

# iApplicants™ Applicant Tracking System – Privacy Policy

|  |   
More Applicants:  
---  
Company Website Visitors  
Feed to FREE Job Boards  
Search Engine Optimization  
Pay-Per-Click Job Marketing  
Email Job Blasting & RSS  
  
Careers Website:  
Careers Website Design  
Automated Job Alerts  
Manage Job Listings  
Employment Applications  
Career Site Traffic Analytics  
Why Buy a .JOBS Domain  
.JOBS Domains Solution  
  
Application Process:  
Custom Application  
Job Specific Questions  
Manage Applicant Flow  
  
Applicant Screening:  
Qualification Screening  
Initial Interview Questions  
Behavioral Interview Questions  
Manage Applicant Flow  
Employment Screening  
  
Reporting & Tracking:  
Applicant Source Tracking  
EEO Compliance Reports  
Affirmative Action Log  
Career Site Visitor Tracking  
  
Partners & Integrations:  
Hiring Assessments  
Background Checks  
HRIS  
Payroll Software  
Employer Tax Credits  
  
Corporate Information:  
About iApplicants™  
Contact iApplicants™  
Request Information  
Partner Programs  
Reseller Program  
Affiliate Program  
iApplicants™ is committed to privacy of personal information gathered during the application process and stored by the iApplicants™ Applicant Tracking System. It is our policy to respect applicant’s privacy and the privacy of corporate records concerning personal information. If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please direct your questions to privacy@iapplicants.com. 

iApplicants™ seeks to follow privacy practices adhering to the Safe Harbor standards.

Please be aware that iApplicants™ is not responsible for the privacy and security practices of our employer clients. iApplicants™ is a system to manage and store application data, but the application information that you enter into one of our client’s sites is the property of the client. If you have questions or concerns about the policies or procedures of a specific employer who is one of our clients, please contact them directly. The following information pertains to the iApplicants™ system and our processing and storage of application information. It is not enforceable upon our employer clients, as they set their own privacy and security practices as to who has access to your data and how they protect and manage the security and privacy of that data.

## Collecting Information 

Personally Identifiable information is collected in a number of sections throughout the iApplicants™ Application process. Applicants have the choice to enter information by completing an application through one of our client's online applicant tracking system. 

Applicants are not required to give any personal information during job “searching” stage of the application process. All information requested directly relates to the job “application” process. Applicant data is then stored to allow company managers to use during their hiring process and to allow for future position consideration and placement. iApplicants™™ does not collect any Social Security numbers during any of its processes to protect the financial identity of its applicants. 

## Choice

All applicants are given an optional choice to provide additional information with regards to EEO Compliance. This information should not affect the applicants’ ability to be considered or hired for open positions., but it is the responsibility of the client to ensure that this policy is enforced.

## Correction/Updating Personal Information

Information can be corrected and updated at any point in the application process by logging into the iApplicants™ Tracking System or by emailing the hiring manager. 

If an applicant's personally identifiable information changes iApplicants™ provides a way to correct, update, or remove that user's personal information. This can be done by logging into the client's iApplicant Applicant Tracking System. 

## Client Privacy Policies 

Please be aware that iApplicants™™ is not responsible for the privacy and security practices of its clients. iApplicants™™ encourages users read the privacy statements of each and every company to which they apply. This privacy statement applies solely to the role iApplicants™™ plays in collecting and storing applicant data. 

## Dissemination of Information 

iApplicants™ will not sell or otherwise transfer any personally identifying information to a 3rd party except for the specific client where an application is filled out. The iApplicant Tracking System allows administrators to contact applicants by e-mail or other electronic means, as well as forwarding applicants application information to other hiring managers in the company for which the applicant has applied. All e-mail generated from iApplicants™ is integral to the use of the application. However, if you would like to opt-out of e-mail, please see the "Opting-Out" section below. 

## Opting-Out 

If you would like to opt-out of any iApplicants™ Applicant Tracking System e-mailings, please e-mail us at privacy@iapplicants.com and put "Opt-out" in the subject heading. You may also simply leave the email field blank on the application, or enter “do not email me” in the email address field. 

## Security 

Personally identifiable information is stored on a separate server as a security precaution and our site is SSL encrypted. Since, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information our users transmit to our Site. 

All applicant information is restricted by administrative login to the iApplicants™ Applicant Tracking System and controlled by the corporate office. Only administrators who have permission are granted access to personally identifiable information. All iApplicants™ employees are kept up-to-date on security and privacy practices. Additionally, the servers that store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure environment that can only be accessed with a secure login and badge access to the facility. 

The access and use of applicant information by our individual clients’ employees who have an administrative login is controlled and regulated by the individual clients. It is up to each of our individual clients to manage who has access to the administrative logins and to ensure that their own employees are kept up-to-date on security and privacy practices. 

For any questions regarding iApplicants™ security or privacy policy, please email us at privacy@iapplicants.com or call 888-633-9269. 

|  |   
---  
  
"I have found tremendous value with the iApplicants™ system. The system shortens the hiring process dramatically and saves us valuable time and resources."   
_**David - Managing Partner**_

"I would recommend using the iApplicants™ System to anyone who wants to make things easier for themselves."  
 _ **Jennie - HR Director**_

"We would be hard pressed to find anything but positives regarding iApplicants™! We look forward to continued use of the system, and cannot imagine returning to paper-based applications."   
_**Kevin - General Manager**_
